## LITTHIDETH (LIT) PHANSIRI

Cell: (206) 369-8894 phansiri@uw.edu

As a career Marine, I've continued to strive to fulfill the duties/assignments given to me. Over the past 14.5 years, I have consistently performed above and beyond expectations and contributed to the success of the missions/projects that I participated in.

#### PROFESSIONAL CAREER

- GitHub Repo
  - o https://github.com/phansiri?tab=repositories
- Computer Lab Manager, Seattle, WA September, 2016 March, 2017 Proposed a grant to the Student Technology Fee Committee for a tech refresh for the University of Washington Clark Hall building that house the Air Force, Army, and Navy ROTC. The planning and set up for two computer labs was done with no supervision. Every key decision on how the computer lab will be ran was at my discretion. Created a lab environment utilizing open source imaging and cloning software called the "Fog Project". Created new position with specific jobs in order to continue maintaining the computer labs. Technologies utilized: Windows 10, Windows server 2012 R2, Hyper-V for Ubuntu 14 and the Open Source Fog Project
- Program Manager, Seattle, WA
   June, 2016 September, 2016

   Read 17 undergraduate and graduate resumes and placed them into specific cross company project teams depending on their strength's and weakness's. Structured outline for four different projects in a way that the respective company can self-sustain the projects after completion. Guided each team through training or providing examples to reach goals of the sponsors.
  - Microsoft
    - o Sorry Application
      - iOS application that lets the user record "Sorry" as well as "Not Sorry" and provide trends and analysis on the data through aggregation.
  - Starbucks
    - Optimization Software
      - Collaborated with Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) to validate and update their software in order to provide an accurate predictive model of stores.
    - o Transportation Mapping
      - Utilize the R project in scripting a way to index unique key terms in order to quickly search for known results.
    - o Holiday Dashboard
      - Interacted with upper management and VP's through various departments of Starbucks in order to create an integrated logistics dashboard for high level visibility.
- Informatics Capstone, Seattle, WA

  Applied the culmination of knowledge gained from my courses to develop a product. The project was for the Mount Rainier National Parks in creating a new reservation system to replace their 15 years old current system. The project started from: understanding their current system through site visits and interviews, defining a concrete problem within the scope of the course, ideating different prototypes, gathering feedback on the prototypes, applying the feedback into a mock version, developing the backend and frontend, and presenting the web application to the stakeholders.

  Capstone site: <a href="https://ischool.uw.edu/capstone/projects/2016/mt-rainier-wilderness-reservation-system">https://ischool.uw.edu/capstone/projects/2016/mt-rainier-wilderness-reservation-system</a>
  Informatics Interview: <a href="https://ischool.uw.edu/feature-stories/informatics-students-challenge-making-new-rainier-reservation-system">https://ischool.uw.edu/feature-stories/informatics-students-challenge-making-new-rainier-reservation-system</a>
- Research Assistant, Seattle, WA
   September, 2015 March, 2017

   Translate raw data into Microsoft SQL Server 2008. Then validate to ensure correctness. Afterwards, migrate Microsoft SQL server to PostgreSQL database in order to use it in a python program utilizing the Django webframe.
- Student Company Commander for Bulldog Company, Seattle, WA February, 2016 June 2016 Planned and administered all events to 28 Midshipmen and 2 Marines in order to basically train and cultivate the next generation Naval and Marine Corps officers.

## • ECHS Teacher's Homestay, Seattle, WA June - September, 2015

The homestay program for international students from various age and level of English to learn in a teacher's home

## Consultant

System analysis of their database and website through the system context, identified stakeholder and requirements, behavioral structural analysis, security analysis and design, and rough cost/benefit analysis. Utilizing Google App Script to provide an improved workflow for a better cost effective way to do business. Migrated their email service to a dedicated web hosting service.

#### CONNX Solutions, Redmond, WA April – June, 2015

Cooperative program hosted by University of Washington

# Data Movement Developer

Designed, created data models and data flows for the data synchronization of corporate relational, cloud, 'Big Data' and legacy database systems. Constructed instructional videos for use on corporate website. Worked with executive management and IT to understand specifications, logical processes and architecture. Collaborated with a team of three interns, sales, engineering and IT. Presented an executive overview during bi-weekly status meetings during the development phase.

Synchronized customer list of 47,000+ records from flat file to multiple platforms, including Microsoft SQL Server 2012, Azure and Hadoop

## • Completed Project

- Collaborated in INFO 498 IOS Development in creating a mobile app that EMT to quickly and efficiently document while administering aid.
  - https://github.com/czross/info498-emtdoc
- Designing a game app that will show college students what will be better to wear for certain events in INFO 360 – Design Thinking – willing to show project upon request
- Consulting <a href="https://echsteachershomestay.com">https://echsteachershomestay.com</a> in creating a more efficient way to conduct business for INFO 380 Information System Analysis & Design as a Project Manager for a team of 4.
- Winner of the 2015 Facebook Seattle Student of Color Hackathon for programming a chrome extension called, "Stay Active", that helps promote active life style by getting out of the chair.
- Redesigned the University of Washington Naval Reserve Officer Training Corps website to be more
  in align with how the University conducts business.
  - New site: http://nrotc.washington.edu

# **MILITARY CAREER**

The Basic School

Quantico, Virginia Sept 2017 – March 2018

Position: Student

Currently selected for the 0602 Communications Officer MOS

# Naval Reserve Officer Training Corps (NROTC), University of Washington

Seattle, Washington Sept 2013 – March 2017

Position: Marine Enlisted Commissioning Education Program (MECEP), Student

- Selected as one of the few enlisted Marines to enter into Officer Candidate School (OCS), April 2013
- Ranked in the top 15% (of the 152 candidates) at OCS during the summer of 2013
- · Chief Information Officer that deals with all NROTC student correspondence and the units website
- Provided briefs about Information Assurance to the battalion about best practices on how to secure their data.
- Provided the ROTC building two new computer
- Maintains an active secret clearance since 2008
- Commissioned as a Second Lieutenant on Sept 5, 2017

#### Marine All-Weather Fighter Attack Squadron (VMFA-242)

Marine Corps Air Station, Iwakuni, Japan June 2012 – Sept 2013

Position: Maintenance Administration Division Chief

- Ensured the squadron accurately recorded over 12,000 Maintenance Action Forms, 23,000 direct maintenance man hours, and 3,300 flight hours
- Directly supervised 13 Marines and monitored over 100 maintenance personnel from various units
- Acted as lead and administratively screened and accepted an aircraft which had a non-flyable status since July 2012
- Maintained the organizational level of the Naval Aviation Logistics Command Management Information System (NALCOMIS) for on-site and off-site as lead System Admin/Data Base Manager

#### Marine Corps Recruiting Station Seattle, Recruiting Sub-Station Bellevue

Seattle, Washington July 2009 – May 2012

Position: Recruiting Sub-Station Staff Non-commissioned Officer in Charge

- Directly contributed to the future of the Marine Corps by getting over 25 recruitments
- Developed recruitment strategies and supervised seven Marines
- Provided guidance and counseled future Marines on different opportunities within military service
- Screen applicants to determine eligibility and provide initial training to candidates in the delayed entry program
- Acted as liaison and coordinated training/evaluations with the Military Entrance Processing Station

# Marine Aviation Logistics Squadron (MALS-12) Power Plant Division

Marine Corps Air Station, Iwakuni, Japan May 2006 – April 2009

Position: Logs and Records Non-commission Officer in Charge

- Supported all operations for F/A-18 Hornet, EA-6B Prowler, and Harrier Jump Jet engine/module production
- Positively affected the production of over 1,000 modules and about 200 aircraft engines
- Acted as the lead System Admin/Data Base Manager for the Naval Aviation Logistics Command Management Information System (NALCOMIS)
- Lead a team of 7 Marines and Sailors and ensured engines/modules were ready for issue and transferred over 3,400 units worldwide

Awards: Two Navy and Marine Corps Achievement Medals, for directly contributing to a 300% production increase over the previous quarter and raising an additional 30% engine module production by optimizing efficiency

#### Marine TiltRotor Operational Test and Evaluation Squadron (VMX-22)

Marine Corps Air Station New River, North Carolina Feb 2004 - May 2006

Position: Material Expediter and Maintenance Administration Clerk

- Expedited and supported intermediate level supply activities to ensure work centers had necessary materials in a timely manner
- · Maintain accurate and proper record keeping as squadron grew from three aircraft to twenty
- Assisted in testing and evaluation of the V-22 Osprey prior to them integrating into individual Marine units
- Mentored seven Marines; providing counseling, guidance and annual evaluations

Award: Navy and Marine Corps Achievement Medal, for greatly impacting the transfer of 20 MV-22B Osprey and supported an additional detachment of four aircrafts.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Washington, Seattle, WA

Fall 2013 - Winder 2017

- Earned a Bachelor's of Science on March 2017 in the major called Informatics with double concentration in Information Assurance & Cyber Security and Information Architecture.
- GPA: 3.63
- Earned the Annual Dean's List (pre-req is to make the Dean's List every quarter for the year) for 2015 and 2016

Central Texas College, Marine Corps Air Station (MCAS) Iwakuni, Japan Fall 2008

• Total credit hours: 6 semester hours

#### University of Maryland University College, MCAS Iwakuni, Japan Fall 2006 - Fall 2008

- Total credit hours: 25 semester hours
- Certificate of successful completion of the course of study in Japanese Studies

## Kansas University, Lawrence, KS Summer 2003

Total credit hours: 5 quarter hours

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Database Administrator and Systems Administrator
- Java, Python, the R Project, and Swift
- Cloud: Azure and AWS
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Bootstrap, lo-dash, Angularis, and PHP
- Microsoft SQL Server 2008 and 2012, Unix/Linux based OS
- Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB
- Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, and Outlook
- Drupal, Joomla and Wordpress
- Django framework for server side web development and Google App Script
- Extract, Transform, and Load (ETL) data for multi-dimensional databases
- SQL to SQL data movement
- NoSQL to SQL data movement
- Azure to SQL data movement
- Hardware maintenance
- Entity Relationship Diagram, Activity Diagram, Data Flow Diagram, Site Mapping, User Flow Diagram, and Wire-framing
- Penetration Testing, Ethical Hacking
- Systems Virtualization
- Networking: OSI model, IPv4 subnetting, security, routing, 802.11

## Personal Accomplishments:

- Completed the MCAS Iwakuni 20<sup>th</sup> Japanese & American Goodwill Sprint Triathlon
- Completed the MCAS Iwakuni 41st Annual Kintai Marathon
- Completed the MCAS Iwakuni 19th Japanese & American Goodwill Sprint Triathlon
- Brown Belt in Marine Corps Martial Arts
- Water Survival Qualified (highest level in annual training)
- Consistently achieving First Class in physical and combat fitness test (semi-annual)